Ahsan Ghazni Khan



m: 03345255087 Address: house# 283, street# 86, E11/2, Islamabad email: ahsan123pk@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Secure a responsible career opportunity to fully utilize my training and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company or department.

PROFILE

I have 4 years experience of Mobile Software Applications Development for Apple iOS platform. I have done training and courses in Artificial intelligence and data science. I have also worked on machine learning deep learning. I am confident, friendly and approachable meaning I work well with new people. I'm a quick learner with a keen eye for detail. Being highly motivated and an ambitious person, I'm not afraid to put in the hard work necessary. Due to many new experiences I can adapt well to new situations. I give my optimal performance every time something is expected of me and I can work well within a team.

DIRECTORATE OF ELECTRONIC MEDIA & PUBLICATIONS (DEMP)

News media monitor and angler at DEMP News Media Monitoring Department of Ministry of Information & Broadcasting.

BLOCHCHAIN

- Was enrolled in PIAIC blockchain program (2019).
- Know about blockchain working and its concepts.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Javascript (Visual Studio)
- Languages: C, C++, Java, Java Swing, J2EE, Servlet, JSP, Spring & Hibernate, Objective-C, Swift, Python
- Productivity Software Tools (Integrated Development Environments): Borland Turbo C, C++, Eclipse, Xcode, PyCharm, Juyter Notebook.

WEB DEVELOPMENT SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- PHP, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Web development Trainee at Microverse.org
- Java Spring Framework, Spring MVC
- Spring hybernate

DATA SCIENCE AND ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE CERTIFICATIONS

- Six Weeks Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Training at Accentedge (2019)
- Hands on Data Science withn Anaconda (2019)
- Mahine Learninng A-Z -- Hands on Python (2019)

EDUCATION

Allama Iqbal Open University – Islamabad 2006 – 2010

Bachelors of Science (Computer Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Data Bases)

64%, B grade

Punjab College of Information Technology – Islamabad 2004 – 2006

ICS (English, Urdu, Pakistan Studies, Islamic Education, Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science): 537/1100

Islamabad Model of College for Boys – G-10/4, Islamabad 2001 – 2003

Matric (English, Urdu, Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Islamiyat, Pakistan Studies): 391/850

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEMP (July 2021-October 2021)

News media monitor and angler at DEMP News Media Monitoring Department of Ministry of Information & Broadcasting.

Accentedge (Feb 2019-March 2019)

- I have done data science training including machine learning and deep learning in python programming language and also did job their for one month, worked as a cloud engineer.
- I have used different tools such as jupyter notebook.
- I have installed anaconda software and worked on it.

Independent Completed Projects (2016-2017)

Music Library & Shopping Cart in JSP and Servlets (June 2017 – July 2017)

I have made this web app independently in Center of Development and Excellence J2EE Student

• MathKido (April 2017 –May 2017)

I have made this IOS app independently.

• HyFind (March 2016 – May 2016)

Apple Developer Program/ Mobile Applications Developer (iOS Developer).

NineSol Technologies, (2014 - 2015)

Iphone and Ipad apps development, Usability Testing, Functional Testing, Black Box testing, Gray Box Testing, HTML use in iOS apps.

Name of assignment / Project:	Blood Type Diet, NineSole Technologies
Company:	NineSol Tecnologies
Year:	May 2015 – May 2015
Main features of the Project:	Blood Type Diet is a handy iOS app designed to educate
	people with respect to their Blood Group.
Position held:	Mobile Applications Developer
Name of assignment / Project:	6 Kalmas of Islam
Year:	April 2014 – May 2014
Company:	NineSol Technologies
Main features of the Project:	6 Kalmas of Islam is an application in which people can
	recite Kalmas of Islam with perfect pronunciation and
	translation.

Mobile Media City, (2011-2013)

iOS apps developer and tester

Name of assignment / Project:	King Prison Bre	raker
Year:	Jan 2013 - Mar 2013	
Location:	Islamabad	
Company:	MobileMediaCity	
Main features of	This is an iOS 2D game developed in Cocoas2D,	
the Project:	framework of iOS in which there is a thief who is escaping from Jail	
	and police is chasing him.	
Name of assignment / Project:		Budget Cash & Carry
Year:		Sep 2012 – Jan 2013

Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity
Position held:	Mobile Applications Developer (iOS Developer)
Name of assignment / Project:	Math Hippo
Year:	Jan 2012 – Feb 2012
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity
Main features of the Project:	This ios application is a 2D video game for kids.
Name of assignment / Project:	Alpha Hippo,
Year:	Feb 2012 – Mar 2012
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity
Main features of the Project:	An educational game that shows a picture of anything like food item, animal, or an Alphabetical letter.

Name of assignment / Project:	Learn A Sign
Year:	Dec 2011- Jan 2012
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity
Main features of the Project:	This is a handy iOS application that teaches different signs and postures to communicate with deaf people.

Name of assignment / Project:	Home Tasks Management
Year:	Aug 2011 – Dec 2011
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity
Main features of the Project:	This handy iOS application helps the user do any task that
	is to be done on a specific time and day.
Name of assignment / Project:	Calories Explorer
Year:	Jul 2011 – Aug 2011
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	MobileMediaCity

Main features of the Project:	This is a handy iOS application that tells the user that any
	food item per serving contains how much
	calories, Fat, Saturated Fat, Unsaturated Fat, Polyunsaturated
	Fat, Energy, Sugar, Proteins, others

Discretelogix Pvt Ltd, Islamabad, Pakistan (2013-2013

IOS developer and tester

Name of assignment / Project:	Alsummit
Year:	2013
Location:	Islamabad
Company:	Discretelogix Pvt Ltd.
Main features of the Project:	This application is a handy iOS application to set namaz
	timings and setting the phone into silent mode during
	namaz. This application is for Cydia.

Birbeck International School, Islamabad, Pakistan (2008-2010)

G. W Basic Computer language teacher. (class 9th & 10th)

References

Available for each project on demand.